





# WHO AM I?

Software engineering manager with over 10 years experience developing for the web in a multitude of languages, highly collaborative with an excellent understanding of development best practices throughout the entire SDLC Experience owning & crafting product / technical road maps collaborating with both clients and technical stakeholders to many successful deliveries.

Enjoys working closely with HR & Recruiting to hire and build high performing agile teams of 6-12 people

Leadership, team building & management

Full Stack Developer

Devops

Agile Methodologies

Product Management

## **EXPERIENCE**

4/2019 - 4/2020 Los Angeles, USA

#### **Engineering Manager**

GOAT

Lead, recruited & managed a team of 15 comprising of iOS (Swift) / Android (Kotlin) / Backend Engineers (Ruby/Golang Micro-services) both co-located and remote, building and successfully delivering on alias a brand new app & brand for GOAT

Worked with PM's and key stakeholders to execute & deliver utilizing a combination of agile methodologies on an entirely new app & brand

6/2017 - 7/2018 Melbourne, Australia

#### **Solutions Architect**

Travelport Locomote

Product Strategy

Pragmatically defined & owned the product technology roadmap and set strategic direction to teams through deep collaboration with product owners, engineers, QA & other stakeholders, roadmap artifact were created in the form of user stories & through visual language eg. UML

Worked with HR and Recruiting to recruit staff & improve the hiring process / pipeline

Championed key initiatives to increase release predictability & reliability, reducing cycle time, reducing escaped defects through collaboration with multiple facets of the business such as management, support, sales & engineering

Selected and evangelized design patterns & processes to help scale the architecture & organization with contribution to the organization's wiki, lightning talks & mentoring resulting in improvements to the organizations engineering conceptual integrity & reduced cycle time for user stories

Orchestrated a zero downtime organization wide migration to Heroku (PaaS) from Ansible/Chef managed infrastructure, this resulted in a reduced operational overhead on the engineering team & direct cost savings through a reduction in hosting costs.

Developed technical tools to aid in story visibility through the development pipeline & defect tracking/resolution

Maintained a suite of apps hosting in AWS using Config Management (Ansible/Chef) & PaaS such as Elastic Beanstalk, Heroku and containerization using Docker

Provided direction/planning to engineering teams and collaborated with third party vendors in order to meet PCI / GDPR compliance

6/2014 - 7/2017 Melbourne, Australia

### **Engineering Manager / Technical Product Owner**

**Travelport Locomote** 

Built, hired, mentored & lead scrum teams of 6-8 composing of (Engineers, QA's and BA's) both domestically and remotely, worked closely with HR & Recruiting both locally & abroad nurturing a much lauded company culture that emphasized ownership and collective impact

Fostered continuous improvement and provided continuous feedback to employee's with one on one's and frequent engagement

Facilitated growth of the company from 5 - 50 employee's through formulation & articulation of the vision and goals to scrum teams via story mapping sessions, five whys, kick off's, pair programming & mentoring & improvements to documentation & processes

Orchestrated plans, prioritized resources and set the strategy for on-boarding some of Australia's largest Banks & Universities

Forged and build relationships outside engineering in marketing and support to ensure alignment

Crafted, evangelized and delivered on both the product strategy & the technical roadmap utilizing a stack of Rails/node.js/Heroku/AWS

Identified key differentiators & opportunities through user & sales feedback, backlog and competitor analysis within the market and crafted user stories to guide & fortify the companies USP

Guided product decisions through empiricism primarily through the build, measure lean feedback loop

Supported and collaborated with third parties through acquisition due diligence resulting in a successful buy out

7/2012 - 6/2014 Melbourne, Australia

### Lead Backend Engineer / Engineering Manager

Travelport Locomote

Built, lead, supported & mentored scrum teams of 6-8 as a servant leader both domestically and remotely to many successful deliveries utilizing a stack of Rails/node.js/Heroku/AWS

On-boarded & Supported some of Australia's leading banks and universities, leading to increased revenue/improved market perception

Collaborated and improved hiring, policies and processes for an organization undergoing tremendous growth

Implemented/maintained best practice Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery/Test Automation & Deployment pipelines

3/2006 - 5/2012 Melbourne, Australia

#### Senior Engineer / Lead Backend Engineer

Alliance Software

Delivered E2E & supported over 20 projects with Rails/Zend Framework

Worked with recruiting for hiring and later to lead and mentor junior software engineers

Fostered a spirit of continuous improvement within engineering

Helped build relationships with clients to ensure quality outcomes & manage expectations

Built, managed and supported a custom CMS based on Zend Framework architecture

### **EDUCATION**

2001 – 2004 Melbourne, Australia **Bachelor of Applied Science (Computing)** 

**Swinburne University** 

1998 Melbourne, Australia **Bachelor's Degree** 

Pembroke College